Shivendra Saurav, Frontend Developer



Experienced in using React, Vite and Next frameworks. Led the development of a project for a coffee producer that was deemed "gold standard" by the client. well acquainted with the aspects of UI/UX design and responsible for the design of all projects in the portfolio showcase.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer - LTIMindtree, Bengaluru

May 2022 - Present

- Gathered requirements and concerns from an external client and prepared sprint plans, bot flows, and other documentation.
- Used design specifications and documentation to complete the development of processes within the given timeline.
- Reported concerns and bugs as incidents to the team lead and solved them effectively.

Trainee Engineer - LTIMindtree, Chennai

July 2021 - April 2022

- Provided support to external clients who utilised our services and were using the automation anywhere platform.
- Help with the development and production of bot runners on the Automation Anywhere platform.
- Collection and reporting of status for each process at the end of the day, and creating incidents for processes that failed to further look into the issues that may have led to the failure.

Education

Bachelor of Technology - REVA University, Bengaluru

July 2017 - July 2021

- Graduated with a specialisation in computer science and engineering.
- Core member and Mentor at Google Developers Student Club, REVA University.
- Organised and Participated in many events as member of Hackathon Club, REVA University.

Certifications

Full Stack Web Development with React - Coursera

April 2020 - June 2020

- Course by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.
- Focuses on building Full Stack Web Applications using the MERN Stack.

UI/UX Design - Coursera

January 2020 - March 2020

- Course by The California Institute of the Arts.
- Focuses on building intuitive designs for Mobile and Desktop using The Design Thinking Process.

Skills

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

React

Node JS

Express JS

Flutter

Python

MySQL

Adept In

Web Development

Cross Platform PWAs

Single Page Applications

Responsive Design

UI/UX Design

API Requests

Links

GitHub

LinkedIn

Portfolio